SUMMARY

Cutting-edge blockchain developer with 7 years of experience in software engineering, web development and blockchain development.

Experienced with architecting, developing and deploying smart contracts and decentralized applications, including DeFi, DAO and NFT marketplace, etc.

Advanced knowledge of multiple programming languages, frameworks and extensive familiarity with blockchain infrastructure.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep 2011 - Nov 2015

University of Waterloo, Computer Science Waterloo, ON, Canada

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK WEB3 ENGINEER

Labrys, REMOTE / May 2020 - NOW

- Architected and designed the NFT bridge between Ethereum, Solana and Pastel Network referencing Wormhole and Cosmos IBC protocol
- Built NFT picks application with React, Node.js and integrated payment service with Stripe
- Wrote and test smart contracts for NFT collection with ERC721, audited with MythX and built random-generated NFT resources with Node.js and IPFS
- Wrote scripts to scrap NFTs from Ethereum chain with web3.js
- Integrated smart contracts to frontend applications using **React**, **Web3.js** and **Ethers.js**
- Architected, designed and developed smart contracts for DeFi application using Cosmwasm and Rust.
- Developed smart contracts and frontend application for financial DAO based on Olympus DAO
- Developed smart contracts with Solidity for bonding & staking in Defi application.
- Worked on sports NFT project with Flow/Cadence and React to build a fast, decentralized and developer-friendly blockchain application.
- Integrated Codat service to the backend application for financial accounting, bank, ecommerce integrations
- Integrated Coinbase, Coinmarketcap, Coingecko, Binance api to the Nest.js backend application to sync latest coin data
- Built NFT marketplace application with React, Node.js and Flow framework

COSMOS NETWORK ENGINEER

MixBytes, REMOTE / Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

- Analyzed and researched Cosmos Network and application-specific blockchain development using Golang, Cosmos SDK and Tendermint.
- Architected, designed and developed minimum viable product for applicationspecific blockchain using Golang, Starport and Cosmos.



SHANE **LEWIS**

SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

_

CONTACT

shanelewix@gmail.com 335 Dunsdon St., Brantford, ON, Canada

SOFT SKILLS

Flexibility
Communication
Collaboration
Creativity
Efficiency
Accountability
Self-Innovation
Self-Starter
Critical-Thinking
Problem-Solving

LANGUAGES

JavaScript 8 years
TypeScript 5 years
Python 5 years
Solidity 4 years
Golang 3 years
Rust 3 years
Cadence 2 years

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Integrated Inter-Blockchain Communication Protocol to SDK-based application with Golang.
- Implemented multi-chain smart contract with CosmWasm and Rust.
- Researched and studied **Ethermint**, a scalable, high-throughout Proof-of-Stake blockchain, compatible with **Ethereum**.
- Worked on the frontend application using Vue3 and Quasar framework.

BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

Unicsoft, New York, NY / Feb 2018 - Jun 2020

- Implemented, tested and audited open-source software to interact with on-chain smart contracts.
- Worked on the development and implementations of Defi application with React,
 Solidity and Truffle.
- Architected, developed and deployed ERC20 Cryptocurrency, Smart contracts and web application using Solidity, Hardhat and React.
- Researched and investigated Cosmos SDK and Cosmos Network.
- Wrote technical documentation to communicate key points to stakeholders.

FULL-STACK(FE HEAVY) DEVELOPER

MerixStudio, New York, NY / Dec 2015 - Apr 2018

- Designed, developed and deployed full-stack web applications according to business objectives and needs of various clients with React, Express.js, MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB.
- Improved the page speed by 17% for the ecommerce site that generates \$21M annually in revenue by implementing Code-Splitting and Optimizing performance with React, GraphQL and Apollo.
- Implemented SEO in React application for e-commerce site with a catalog of 20000+ products leading to an increase in page views per session of 23% with SSR in Next.js and Gatsby.
- Built Progressive Web Application (PWA) with React, TypeScript and GraphQL (Relay).
- Worked on building customer-facing web application with Express.js, Prisma, React, PostgreSQL and Node.js.

CERTIFICATIONS

CERTIFIED BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER

Blockchain Council, Sep 2020

CERTIFIED WEB PROFESSIONAL

CIW, Jun 2018



SHANE L**EWIS**

SENIOR BLOCKCHAIN ENGINEER

-

FRAMEWORKS

React	/ years
Vue	5 years
Node.js	5 years
Express.js	5 years
Nest.js	4 years
Hardhat	4 years
Truffle	3 years
Cosmos SDK	3 years
Starport	3 years
Cosmwasm	2 years
Flow	2 years

EXTRA

MySQL PostgreSQL MongoDB GraphQL(Apollo, Relay) Next.js Gatsby Nuxt.js

> Laravel Django

Quasar

Flask

Ethermint

MythX IPFS

Redis

Elastic Search

Docker AWS

Vercel